Guide to the Yale Tocqueville Manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- TOCQUEVILLE & BEAUMONT, AFTER 1840; D.
  - American Relations, 1840-1861; 2
    - a. Tocqueville and Beaumont relations with Americans: letters, diaries, notes, etc. (Box 46)
      -9 July 1852, Paris, E.V. Childe to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -10 Aug. 1852, Boston, George [?] Sumner to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -4 Dec. 1852, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -8 Dec. 1852, Boston, George Sumner to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -4 [?] (dimanche), George Sumner to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -31 Jan. 1853, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -10 March 1853, Jean-Jacques Ampere to Theodore Sedgwick (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -April 1853, American Philosophical Society presents H.D. Gilpin to Tocqueville (GWP note)
      -13 June 1853, Cambridge, Jared Sparks to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -12 July 1853, Jean-Jacques Ampere to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -29 Sept. 1853, Columbia, S. C., Francis Lieber to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -1 Oct. 1853, Boston, Frederick Kidder to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -7 Nov. 1853, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -10 Nov. 1853, Beaumont-le-Roger, Alex Vance to Gustave de Beaumont (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville Mss. "Paquet 12")
      -17 Nov. 1853, N.Y., S. B. Ruggles to Francis Lieber (Robson copy from Hunt)
      -1 Dec. 1853, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -4 Jan. 1854, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -4 March 1854, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton: See C.I.d.)
      -12 March 1854, Columbia, S.C., Francis Lieber to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS. "Paq. 12")
      -22 April 1854, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -30 May 1854, Paris, H.D. Gilpin to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -17 July 1854, Bonn, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -20 July 1854 [?], N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville Mss. "Paquet 12")
      -14 Aug. 1854, Bonn, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -4 Sept. 1854, N.Y., Francis Lieber to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville Mss. "Paquet 12")
      -4 Sept. 1855, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -11 Sept. 1855, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -19 Sept. 1855, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton: See C.I.d.)
      -11 Feb. 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Harper Bros. (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -11 Feb. 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Harper Bros. (Photo from original in Morgan Library)
      -12 Feb. 1856, N.Y., Harper Bros. to Theodore Sedgwick (2X) (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -15 Feb. 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -5 mars 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -23 March 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -29 March 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -18 May 1856, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -21 May 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Harper Bros.: Note and (Photo from Morgan Agreement Lib.)
      -21-23 May 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -28 May 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -6 June 1856, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -29 July 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -July 1856, 9 Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -29 Aug. 1856, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see.C.I.d.)
      -1 7bre 1856, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to Francis Lieber (Photo from Hunt; see B.IV.a.)
      -19 Sept. 1856, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville, (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -14 Oct. 1856, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -10 jan. 1857, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -13 jan. 1857, Boston, E.V. Childe to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville 8 Tocqueville MSS)
      -5 Feb. 1857, Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (draft) (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -(fragment) (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -20 Feb. 1857, Geneva, N.M. B[eckwith] to Tocqueville (long) (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -22 Feb. 1857, Boston, E.V. Childe to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -4 March 1857, Boston, George Sumner to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -27 March, Havana, Edouard Childe to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -13 April 1857, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -2 May 1857, Baltimore, E. V. Childe to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -30 May 1857, N.Y., S. (Susan Sedgwick) [Jardin says Francis Lieber] to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -10 June 1857, Hotel Bristol, George Ticknor to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -13 June 1857, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -11 July 1857, Northampton, Susan and Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -16 July 1857, White Sulphur Springs, E.V. Childe to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -4 Aug. 1857, Athenaeum Club, Charles Sumner to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -7 Aug. 1857, Weymouth near Boston, Maria Weston Chapman to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -20 Sept. 1857, Geneva, Suisse, N.M. B[eckwith] to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -[1857?] en route, N.M. B[eckwith] to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -22 Sept. 1857, Foresthill, Phila., C.J. Ingersoll to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -29 Sept. 1857, Pepperell, Mass., William H. Prescott to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -9 Oct. 1857, Tocqueville St. Pierre Eglise, Tocqueville to Francis Lieber (Photostat from Hunt)
      -30 Oct. 1857, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -14 Nov. 1857, N.Y., P. Tappan to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -30 Nov. 1857, Teddesley Park, Pembridge, Ch. Sumner to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -6 Dec. 1857, "Owlistead"?, Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -8 Dec. 1857, Boston, Edward Everett to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -24 Dec. 1857, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -15 Feb. 1858, N.Y., Theodore Sedgwick to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -28 May 1858, Tocqueville to Theodore Sedgwick (GWP note from MHS: Norton; see C.I.d.)
      -4 June 1858, Paris, Charles Sumner to ? (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -18 Dec. 18, Geneve, Suisse, N. M. Beckwith to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -28 Dec. 1858, Cambridge, Mass., J. Jared Sparks to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -11 jan. 1859, Paris, Robert Walsh to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      -18 fevr. 1861, Beaumont-la-Chartre, Gustave de Beaumont to Francis Lieber (Photo from Hunt: See See B.IV.a.)
      -20 June (184?), 418 rue St. Honore, George Sumner to Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -n.d., unidentified to Tocqueville about portraits (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 12")
      See also Sparks, Hawkins articles, etc. (Noted in E.IV.b.)
    - b. Tocqueville and Beaumont Honors in United States (Box 46)
      -21 Jan. 1832, American Philosophical Society, Philadelphia, Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 10")
      -6 Feb. 1833, Historical Society of Pennsylvania to Tocqueville and to Gustave de Beaumont Notices of election to honorary membership. (from Larminat)
      -10 July 1833, Historical Society of Pennsylvania, Honorary election to Gustave de Beaumont (from Larminat)
      -10 July 1833, Historical Society of Philadelphia [?], Honorary to Gustave de Beaumont (GWP note from Beaumont-la-Chartre)
      -7 Sept. 1838, Rhode Island Historical Society, Providence, Tocqueville certificate Hon. member (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 10")
      -12 Oct. 1838, Rhode Island Historical Society, Providence, Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 10")
      -30 Sept. 1841, American Whig Society of College of N.J. Princeton, Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 10"; Also White note of same)
      -17 May 1844, Smithsonian, corresponding member, Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 10")
      -1 Aug. 1846, Prison Association of N.Y., corresponding member [Tocqueville?] (GWP note from ?)
      -14 May 1857, Massachusetts Historical Society, honorary member, Tocqueville (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 10")
      -n.d., Tocqueville letter accepting, (draft) (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS, "Paquet 10")
  - Tocqueville Life and Career, 1840-1859; 3
    - a. Correspondence, 1840-1865 (Box 47)
      -[1 janvier 1841], vendredi matin, Tocqueville to (Mignet?) (Original from Larminat)
      -17 fevrier 1841, Tocqueville to Paul Premont (Bought from Beres, 4 Sept. 1969)
      -26 juin 1841, Paris, Tocqueville to [Mignet?] (Original from Larminat)
      -10 9bre 1841, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to Dupin aine (acquired by purchase, 1959)
      -13 avril 1844, Caen, Harou-Romain to Tocqueville (Original from Larminat)
      -7 juillet 1844, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient. (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -11 9bre 1844, Paris, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient. (acquired by purchase, 1962)
      -18 mai 1845, Paris, Tocqueville to Cremieux (Original from Larminat)
      -23 7bre 1847, Paris, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient (acquired by purchase, 1957)
      -March 1848, Tocqueville to Mary Mottley (White extract from ?; see C.I.b.)
      -[7 8bre 1848] vendredi soir, Paris, Tocqueville to Jean-Jacques Ampere. (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -7 8bre 1848, Paris, Tocqueville to Roussel (Original from Larminat)
      -27 9bre 1848, Paris, Tocqueville to Didier (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -jeudi (1848?), Tocqueville to Le Mansoit Duprey [?] (acquired by purchase, 1957)
      -4 juin 1849, L.S. Tocqueville to Mallefille at Lisbon (acquired by purchase, 1963)
      -20 juin 1849, Paris, Tocqueville to Admiral Cecille (acquired by purchase, 1970)
      -8 juillet 1849, Paris, Tocqueville to Caraniere? (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -28 juillet 1849, Paris, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -23 janvier 1850, Paris, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -28 April 1850, Paris, Tocqueville to Eugene Stoffels (White Extract from ?; see C.I.b.)
      -6 juin 1850, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to Gosselin. (Gift of Douglas Ewing, 1969)
      -20 mai 1851, Paris, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient (acquired by purchase, 1955)
      -21 Xbre 1851, Tocqueville to a printer (acquired by purchase, 1961)
      -26 Xbre 1851, Metz, Eugene Stoffels [?] to unidentified recipient (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      -31 August 1852, Tocqueville to Francois Villemain (acquired by purchase, 1977)
      -8 mai 1853, Paris, Tocqueville to Sedwick [?] (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -1 dec. 1853, St. Cyr, Tocqueville to Freslon (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -22 jan, 1854, St. Cyr, Tocqueville to Freslon (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -30 juillet 1854, Bonn, Tocqueville to Freslon (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -August 1855, Tocqueville to Mary Mottley (White extract from ?; see C.I.b.)
      -29 dec. 1855, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to Freslon (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -dimanche 1856-57, London, Tocqueville to My Lord (Original from Larminat)
      -20 sep 1856, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to Freslon (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -8 oct 1856, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to Freslon (acquired by purchase, 1965)
      -2 July 1857, London, Tocqueville to Mary Mottley (White extract from ?: See C.I.b.)
      -31 juillet 1857, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient (about sending for Lord Radnor's pigs) (Original from Larminat)
      -24 7bre 1857, Tocqueville, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient (acquired by purchase, 1958)
      -ce 31 8bre (1857?), Tocqueville to Auguste (acquired by purchase, 1957)
      -3 July 1860, Louis de Kergorlay to Mary Mottley (White extract from ?; see C.I.b.)
      -28 juin 1865, Comte de Falloux to Gustave de Beaumont (Photo from Larminat)
      -mardi soir, Tocqueville to Mme Austin. (acquired by purchase, 1960)
      -vendredi matin, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient. "La faconde academique de notre ami Cousin..." (original from Larminat)
      -vendredi matin, Paris, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient. "Le soir meme... je suis tombe malade..." (Original from Larminat)
      -vendredi matin, Tocqueville to M. Corcelles. "Mon cher ami, comme l'affaire..." (Purchase, 1965)
      -"vendredi 1 h.", Tocqueville to unidentified recipient about a luncheon for Lechevalier. (acquired by purchase)
      -dimanche matin, Paris, Tocqueville to unidentified recipient, "Je n'ai point oublie vos interets." (Original from Larminat)
      -no date, Tocqueville to M. Forgues, about a review article (acquired by purchase)
      -no date, Tocqueville to unidentified about M. Raudot (acquired by purchase, 1963)
      -"ce samedi soir [?]", Tocqueville to the Editor of Monitor [?] [M. Grun?] (acquired by purchase, 1969)
      -vendredi matin, Paris, Tocqueville to Coquerel. (acquired by purchase, 1970)
      -vendredi matin, Paris, Tocqueville to an unidentified recipient, possibly George Henry Lewes. "J'ai exprime hier a M. Guizot le desir...' (acquired by purchase, 1971)
      -no date, Tocqueville to Freslon. (acquired by purchase, 1965)
    - b. Tocqueville Notes, Speeches, Writings, Pamphlets - 1840-1859. (Box 48)
      1. Axiomes d'economie politique. 1 p. (Larminat)
      2. Voltaire a dit..." 3 pages (Larminat)
      3. Tocqueville as Foreign minister. Document addressed to the King of Sardinia, signed by L. N. Bonaparte and A. de Tocqueville, Paris, 6 Oct. 1849.
      4. Printed documents.
      -21 avril 1842, Discours de M. de Tocqueville at the Academie francaise on M. de Cessac.
      -2 Dec. 1851, Derniere seance de l'Assemblee Nationale
      -3 avril 1852, Discours de M. de Tocqueville, Academie des sciences morales et politiques.
      -14 juillet 1866, Lettre sur les derniers moments d'Alexis de Tocqueville Comte Ed. de Tocqueville a Mignet.
      -"Faire-part" of Tocqueville's death, 16 avril 1859.
      5. Printed document: "A Messieurs les electeurs du Canton de Montebourg." Tocqueville's letter of retirement to his constituency. 29 avril 1852.
      6. Tocqueville Estate and Household Accounts (1856-1859):
      -Contract [?] de la valeur de toutes les terres de Tocqueville suivant les cadastres (1856).
      -Short list of farm tenures.
      -Scrap on coal and cider.
      -Reglement fait avec Birette, 1 9bre 1857.
      -Conventions avec Birette.
      -Cidre: consommation dans la maison.
      -Salaire de Birette, 8 8bre 1857.
      -Parcelles de terre cedees par le fermier, et contenance du parc et jardin.
      (These were received from Mme de Larminat and after Xerox copies were made for Yale, the originals were sent to Andre Jardin for the Tocqueville archives.)
    - c. Photographs of Tocqueville Chateau etc. (Box 48)
      -with a few calling cards and mementos (see A.IX.)
      -calling cards and addresses. (From Larminat)
    - d. Miscellaneous. (Box 48)
      1. Christian de Tocqueville purchase from Antonin de Beaumont of Alexis de Tocqueville papers, books, and Chasseriau portrait in June 1891. (Bonnel copy from Tocqueville Tocqueville MSS)
      2. Tocqueville family letters. (Gift of GWP)
      -18 Xbre 1847, Baugy, Baron de Tocqueville to unidentified.
      -31 mai 1891, Paris, Comte de Tocqueville to "Madame"
      -17 aout 1907, Vicomte de Tocqueville to unidentified.
      -13 7bre 1907, Vicomte de Tocqueville to St. Germain.
      3. Copy of The Times, 29 July 1955, J.P. Mayer article on "Alexis de Tocqueville and his English friends." (Gift of Edwin J. Beinecke)
    - e. Conversations of Nassau William Senior with Alexis de Tocqueville. (Box 49)
      1848-1858. (4 bound volumes) (From Larminat)
      (For comment, see folder D.III.e.)
    - e. Conversations of Nassau William Senior with Alexis de Tocqueville. (Box 50)
    - f. Lord Hatherton Journal (Box 48)
      1. Extracts from the Journal of Lord Hatherton. (Copied from the original in the Staffordshire Record Office: D260/M/F/5/26/73)
      Copy made by Hugh Brogan for G.W. Pierson and the Yale Tocqueville-Beaumont Collection, January 1965.
      NOT TO BE CITED OR QUOTED OR PUBLISHED IN WHOLE OR IN PART WITHOUT THE WRITTEN CONSENT OF THE PRESENT LORD HATHERTON.
    - g. Letter from Tocqueville to Sarah Austin. 26 Nov 1835. (Box 48)
      Translated and published in Three Generations of English Women, by Janet Ross. London, 1893, p. 121-123.
      Copied by Hugh Brogan and sent by him to the Yale Tocqueville collection.
  - Beaumont Life and Career, 1840-1866; 4
    - a. Song sung by Gustave de Beaumont at marriage of nephew and niece, 23 Nov. 1853. (Copy by Vicomte de Romanet) (Box 51)
    - b. Notes sur le Journal de Senior, 1852. (Original from Larminat) (Box 51)
    - c. Manuscript notes "Sleswig", 29 9bre [1848?] (Original from Larminat) (Box 51)
    - d. 12 avril 1849, Gustave de Beaumont Rapport on Fisherman of Boulogne (Original from Larminat) (Box 51)
    - e. Notes and official letters, Commission de legislation de l'Algerie (with 1876 document) (Original from Larminat) (Box 51)
    - f. Manuscript copy of Bugeaud "Les moyens d'affermir et d'utiliser la conquete d'Algerie" (Original from Larminat) (Box 51)
    - g. 80 pages manuscript draft in another hand on Algeria with some marginal notes by Gustave de Beaumont (Original from Larminat) (Box 51)
    - h. "Transport sur les lieux" draft of letter of 6 janvier, 1842 (Original from Larminat) (Box 51)
    - i. "Libre echange. Angleterre" [1846?] (Original from Larminat) (Box 51)
    - j. "Banques" 124 pages (Original from Larminat) (Box 51)
    - k. Materials on 1848, with newspaper clippings (Original from Larminat) (Box 52)
      -Justice in U.S.; notes on Federal and State constitutions [1846 or after]
      -notes for making a new French constitution; executive power
      -rough notes of seances of 19 May, 25 May, 30 May, 1 June, 15 June 1848, including brief notes on what was said, and by whom in some cases. Also notes for 3 July and some proposals in other hands. And a Tocqueville quote.
    - l.-"24 fevrier 1848" - 101-page manuscript draft (with perhaps 56 pages more) (Original from Larminat) (Box 52)
      -"2 Xbre 1851" First recital. What brought it on? What could have prevented? More than 130 pages (Original from Larminat)
    - m. Gustave de Beaumont Correspondence, 1840-1866. (Box 52)
      -7bre 1842. Memorandum in Gustave de Beaumont's hand. Corruption of electors in July 1842. Long series of questions to English friends on constitutional powers of H. of Commons. Marked as sent 2 8bre 1842 to Hume, Senior, Lewis, Bethune, Sharpe and on 23 9bre to Edw. Everett.
      -17 oct. 1842, Board of Trade, London, G. R. Porter to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -17 oct. 1842, Balfour House, Fife, J.E.A. Bethune to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -22 oct. 1842, By... Sqr. London, Joseph Hume to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -30 Oct. 1842, 32 Chester St., G. L. Lewis to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -6 dec. 1842, 12 Victoria Sqr., Pimlico, copy of J.A. Roebuck to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -16 dec. 1842, By... Sqr. Joseph Hume to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -22 dec. 1842, London [?], N. W. Senior to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -24 Dec. 1842, London, N. W. Senior to Gustave de Beaumont (Larminat)
      -28 juin 1865, Comte de Falloux to Gustave de Beaumont on how he edited the Tocqueville-Mme Swetchine correspondence (Larminat to GWP)
    - n. French edition of La Cabane de l'Oncle Tom with Gustave de Beaumont's signature (Original from Larminat) REMOVED FOR SEPARATE PRINTED ITEM CATALOGING (VAG/nlb 12/96) (Box 53)
    - o. Miscellaneous: (Box 53)
      -11 avril 1843, letter from Joseph de Wurst... [to Gustave de Beaumont?]
      -Beaumont Chateau photo cards (see also A.IX.)
      -"Gustave de Beaumont: Liberal" by GWP
      -B. Fabian's review of translation of Marie with introduction by Alvis L. Tinnin
    - p. Documents of National Assembly, 1874 (Original from Larminat) (Box 53)
    - q. 5 Dessins de Cannes, by Gustave de Beaumont when Tocqueville was dying (1859) (Larminat to GWP) (Box 53)
      Missing: (bought by Yale but not sent)
      -Algerie et Afrique several doct. incl.
      -Gustave de Beaumont rapport sur l'Algerie, 93 pages
      -Observations sur Afrique, 29 juin 1846, by Lt. Gl. de la Moriciere.
      -Bugeaud sur la colonization, 1841.
      -other docts. on Algeria.
      -Enquete electorale
      -40 pages plus. 22 avril 1843. ever printed?
      -Elections de 1848-9
      -60 letters of Gustave de Beaumont.
      -English budget
      -extracts from English press, 1843.
      -Texas
      -newspapers and notes on the annexation of Texas, 1845. Also article in La Revue Independante.
      -Newspapers and pieces generales, etc.
    - r. Letters by Gustave de Beaumont (Box 53)
      -Gustave de Beaumont to his wife, Clementine de Lafayette (with sleeve in her hand: "Lettres de Gustave, annee 1859 voyage a Cannes")
      -undated, Paris, lundi matin, apparently about the schoolwork of their son, Antonin (blue paper, mature hand) (Larminat to GWP)
      -part of a letter on blue paper of a different shade, signed by Gustave, but undated (Larminat to GWP)